Akash Sahu

I am a senior software engineer with 8 years of experience in mobile app development and game development. I love doing programming, solving problems and I like to work on challenging and visionary projects. I always try to do my best and try to justify my role in the organization.

Shivaji Nagar, Dhanbad - 828301 +91-8298050156 akash22october@gmail.com

EXPERIENCE

PTWI India Pvt Ltd, Bangalore - Senior Software Engineer March 2023 - present

I worked as a senior software engineer to build a prototype game with Unity DOTS.

Think & Learn Pvt Ltd(Byjus), Bangalore— Senior Software Engineer

Sept 2017- march 2023

- I worked as a senior software engineer in a team to build a gamification educational app for lower grades kids.
- designed and implemented many complex features like study plan, recommendation engine, search engine, templates for making quiz games.
- optimized app performance and optimized the build size of the
- Fixed many critical bugs in the app.
- designed app backend api services.

Dumadu Games, Bangalore— *Game developer*

April 2015- 2016

- I worked as a game developer where I developed multiple 3D mobile games for Android and IOS.
- Optimized game performance
- Implemented a player controller for lawn tennis game for TVOS platform by using gyro sensor. fixed many critical bugs in the production

EDUCATION

Asansol Engineering College, Asansol— B.Tech

August 2009 - July 2013

I have done my B.tech in electronics and communication engineering. I learnt a lot of things in my college like programming, robotics, operating systems, DBMS, Analog and Digital transmissions etc.

SKILLS

- data structure and algorithms
- Unity 3d
- **OOPS**
- **Unity DOTS**
- git
- **SQLite**
- python
- ML Beginner
- shader programming
- debugging
- IIRA

AWARDS

Recognised in monthly R&R and got rewarded twice for my perseverance.

LANGUAGES

English, Hindi, Bengali

HOBBIES

Cricket, Badminton, Cycling

PROJECTS

Asteroids - Asteroids is a space-themed unidirectional shooter arcade video game developed with Unity ECS concept.

Disney Byju's early learn – DBEL is an educational app for lower grades kids. it contains videos, interactive videos, games and gamified UI for engaging kids.

app link -

https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.byjus.k3&hl=en_IN&gl=US&pli=1

3D Bowling - 3D bowling is a game based on bowling game for Android, IOS and TVOS